# Miao Sun

CONTACT Information Department of ECE

347 Engineering Building West University of Missouri Columbia, MO 65211 USA Voice: (573) 825-7950

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} $E$-mail: & msqz6@mail.missouri.edu \\ $Homepage: $http://vision.ece.missouri.edu/$ \end{tabular}$ 

RESEARCH INTERESTS Computer vision with special interests in object detection, image classification, and activity analysis; Machine learning with special interests in local learning and transfer learning.

**EDUCATION** 

### University of Missouri, Columbia, MO USA

Ph.D. Candidate in Electrical and Computer Engineering

GPA: 4.0/4.0

• Thesis Topic: "Adaptive Object Detection in Large Scale Database"

• Advisor: Prof. Tony X. Han

## University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei China

Bachelor of Engineering, Dept. of Automation, July, 2011

Weighted score: 88.94/100

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### University of Missouri, Columbia, MO USA

Research Assistant of Professor Tony X. Han

Aug. 2011 - present

# • Object Detection for PASCAL VOC Challenge

Under the direction of Professor Tony X. Han, I was the key personnel of the MU object detection team for the PASCAL VOC challenge. We ranked 7th worldwide. In our team, I was in charge of:

- 1.HOG-LBP feature extraction:
- 2.Deformable model training using latent SVM;
- 3.Post-processing through context re-scoring to boost the final performance.

### • Action Recognition Using Bag of HOG Variations

We developed a mid-level feature, Histogram of Oriented Gradient Variations(HOGV), for action recognition with the bag-of-visual-words model. The HOGV feature is the temporal variation of the stable HOG feature, which is not only stable due to its cell-block structure, but is also capable of capturing the static and dynamic characteristics of human actions. This work has been submitted to the International Conference on Image Processing 2012(ICIP 2012).

#### • The Implementation of Convolutional Neural Network(CNN)

I implemented a Convolutional Neural Network for object recognition based on the paper: Gradient-Based Learning Applied to Document Recognition. I tested the CNN on the UMIST Database, which contains 574 images of 20 individuals. We achieved a testing accuracy of 99.13%. This component has been used for the face localization demo of our lab.

Now, I am focusing on learning hierarchical models which simultaneously represent multiple levels including pixel intensities, edges, object parts, objects, and beyond. Geoffrey E. Hinton's work about using a Restricted Boltzmann Machine to model each new layer of higher level features and Andrew Y. Ng's work about Convolutional Deep Belief Networks, which designs a generative version of the pooling / subsampling units, inspires me to apply a modified Convolutional Neural Network on Deep Architectures. Work will be submitted to the Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2013(CVPR2013)

• Investigating the Possibility of Combining AdaBoost with Sparse Linear SVM I wrote a Linux C++ version of RealBoost based on the paper: Additive Logistic Regression: a

Statistical View of Boosting. I am currently investigating the learning scheme of using RealBoost to select features and combine with sparse linear SVM to improve the performance.

## University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei China

Research Assistant of Professor Zhiqang Zheng.

Oct. 2009 - Apr. 2011

### • Automatic Number Plate Recognition System

- I developed an automatic plate recognition System. The basic steps were as follows:
- 1.Locate license plate using the shape feature;
- 2. Orientation and scale normalization;
- 3. Character segmentation using adaptive histogram-based method;
- 4. Shape feature extraction to recognize the license plate.

## • Robo-game Competition

Jun. 2009 - Sep. 2009

I took part in the robo-game competition in 2009. We were asked to manufacture a biped robot as a boxer. The biped robot was required to have human-like shape and to walk as human beings. The whole process of making such a robot and car can be divided into three parts: mechanical structure, circuit design and programming. I was in charge of the programming part; I developed the control program on the Single-Chip Microcomputer to control the whole system including walking, communication between operators and robots.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Xutao Lv Miao Sun, Tony X. Han, Zhihai He and Shihong Lao, "Action recognition using bag of HOG variations", submitted to ICIP2012.

Computer Skills Languages & Software: C/C++, Python, and Matlab.

Platform: Windows, Linux, Hadoop-based map-reduced clusters.

Software package: OpenCV, STL, LTI-LIB.

#### AWARDS

- Outstanding Student Scholarship (Grade 1), USTC, China, 2010
- Shanghai Institute of Microsystem and Information Scholarship, USTC, China, 2009
- Outstanding Student Scholarship (Grade 1), USTC, China, 2008

#### Reference

### Tony X.Han

Assistant Professor, University of Missouri

Email: hantx@missouri.edu

Phone: 573-882-6630

Homepage: http://web.missouri.edu/~hantx

### Zhihai He

Associate Professor, University of Missouri

Email: hezhi@missouri.edu

Phone: 573-882-3495

Homepage: http://web.missouri.edu/~hezhi